A Finding Aid to the Maryette Charlton papers, circa 1890-2013, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Correspondence, 1930-2010; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 23.3 Linear feet Boxes 4-27, 80
  - Family Correspondence, 1930-2002; 2.1; Archival Resource Key
    - Wedding Congratulations, 1953-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Winslow, Hall - Correspondence with Paul Bowles, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Winslow, Hall - Correspondence with Reza Mossaberi, 1986-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Winslow, Hall, circa 1953-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 7-11)
    - Winslow, Kirk, 1964-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 12-17)
    - Winslow, Kirk, 1990-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
    - Winslow, Kirk - Condolence Letters to Maryette Charlton, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 5-8)
    - YWCA, 1943-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Family Chronological Correspondence, 1930-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 10-17)
    - Family Chronological Correspondence, 1947-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 1-26)
    - Family Chronological Correspondence, 1963-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 1-21)
    - Family Chronological Correspondence, 1972-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 1-17)
    - Family Chronological Correspondence, 1985-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 1-7)
    - Family Postcards, 1945-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Oversized Photographs by Hall Winslow from Box 5, Folder 8, 1953-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 80)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1938-2010; 2.2; Archival Resource Key
    Personal correspondence is arranged alphabetically by name, followed by chronological correspondence. Additional correspondence is found throughout the papers in project files, film project files, and exhibition files, as well as the 2014 addition.
    Personal correspondence includes letters between Maryette Charlton and her friends and colleagues, many of whom were famous artists. Notable correspondents include Jo Andres, Laura Benet, Elizabeth Bishop, Steve and Lucian Buscemi, Xenia Cage, Patrice Caire, Paula Court, Yasuo Fujitomi, Nimet Saba Habachy, Dimitri Hadzi, Margo Hoff, Sylvia Shaw Judson, Lillian Kiesler, Loren MacIver, Patricia Michaels Mason, Barbara Meyer, Henri Seyrig, Scotty Snyder, Nicole Stenger, Diane Thome, and Robert Wilson, among many others. There is also correspondence with colleges, museums, and organizations such as the Chicago Public School System and Pratt Institute. There is 1 sound disc and 1 sound cassette.
    - Adnan, Etel, 1982-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Andres, Jo, 1986-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 10-12)
    - Antioch College, 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 13-14)
    - Benet, Laura, 1971-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Bishop, Elizabeth, 1969-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Breer, Frannie Bob, 1977-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Buehr, George, 1973-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Buscemi, Steve and Lucian, 1989-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Cage, Xenia, 1972-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 20-21)
    - Cage, Xenia, 1975-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 1-3)
    - Caire, Patrice, 1993-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Chicago Public Schools, Archival Resource Key (Box 11)
      - General Correspondence, 1951-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Schedules Correspondence, 1951-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - Arts and Activities Correspondence, 1951-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - Future Projects Correspondence, 1948-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - Thank You Letters, 1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Thank You Letters, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - "Coastal Traces", 1998; Archival Resource Key; Includes 1 sound disc (CD) (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Court, Paula, 1991-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 12-14)
    - Cummings, Marion Morehouse, 1965-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 15-16)
    - Davis, Philip, 1987-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Dixon, Elizabeth Gruse, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - European Correspondence, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Frankenberg, Lloyd, 1961 August-1962 June; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 20-21)
    - Fujitomi, Yasuo, 1960-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 1-17)
    - Gottlieb, Jay, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Habachy, Nimet Saba, 1995-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Habachy, Nimet Saba, 1995-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Hadzi, Dimitri, 1971-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Hagan, John, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Hoff, Margo, 1972-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Holabird, Dorothy, 1973-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Holland, Betty Lou, 1997-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 6-7)
    - Jackson, Dakota, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Judson, Sylvia Shaw, 1958-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Kiesler, Lillian, 1965-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 10-20)
    - Kiesler, Lillian, 1986-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 1-16)
    - Kossoff, Rosalind, 1964-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Kossoff, Rosalind, 1964-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Lubar, Cindy, 1977-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - MacGregor, Mary, 1989-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - MacIver, Loren, 1961-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 4-10)
    - Marini, Aida, 1989-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Mason, Patricia Michaels, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Matisse, Patricia (Kane), 1967-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 13-14)
    - Matisse, Pierre and Maria-Gaetana "Tana", 1967-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - McDowell, Carol, 1994-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - McKnight, Dale and Josephine, 1983-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Meehan, Nancy and Tony Candido, 1971-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Meyer, Albert J., 1976-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Meyer, Annie, 1976-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Meyer, Barbara, 1975-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 2-5)
    - Meyer, Peter, 1983-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Meyer, Steve, 1983-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Miller, Margaret, 1962-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Monticello "Fellows", 1942-1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Monticello "Gals", 1942-1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Myers, Virginia A., 1984-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - "Photography Fan Letters", 1942-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Pratt Institute, 1945-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 13-20)
    - Pratt Institute, 1945-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 1-8)
    - Putney School, 1977-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Reiter, Mary Jo, 1993-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 10)
      Correspondence about a project on Elizabeth Lawrence Kalashnikoff.
    - Roach, Jim, 1951-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Robinson, Antonia Smith, 1989-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Schmidman, Jo Ann and Megan Terry, 1972-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 13-14)
    - Schramm, Dorothy, 1987-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 15-18)
    - Scott, Francis Gruse, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Seyrig, Delphine, 1976-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Seyrig, Fabien, 1994-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Seyrig, Henri, 1960-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Seyrig, Miette, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Seyrig, Miette, 1967-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Seyrig, Miette, 1977-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Shannon, Caty Monnier, 1989-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Smith, Jane Lawrence, 1990-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Snyder, Scotty, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Stenger, Nicole, 1990-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - "Steve", 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Templin, Barbara, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Thome, Diane, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Veret, Jean-Louis and Helene, 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Weiler, Max and Yvonne, 1988-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 15-16)
    - Wilson, Robert, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Youngerman, Duncan, 1982-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 18-20)
    - YWCA, Archival Resource Key (Box 19)
      - General Correspondence, 1943-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Chicago Fellows, 1943-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - Chicago Gals, 1943-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - Postcards, 1943-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Personal Chronological Correspondence, 1938-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 5-17)
    - Personal Chronological Correspondence, 1946-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 1-17)
    - Personal Chronological Correspondence, 1967-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 1-15)
    - Personal Chronological Correspondence, 1980-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 1-14)
    - Personal Chronological Correspondence, 1990-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 1-14)
    - Personal Chronological Correspondence, 1997-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 1-15)
    - Personal Chronological Correspondence, 2001-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 1-15)
    - Personal Chronological Correspondence, 2003-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 1-15)
    - Personal Chronological Correspondence, 2004-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 1-6)
- Writings, 1942-1999; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 1 Linear foot Boxes 27-28
  Writings include Maryette Charlton's academic papers and notes from graduate and undergraduate studies as well as drafts of essays and articles on subjects such as her career, artists she knew, and places she lived.
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  - Monticello College Notes, 1942-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Pratt Institute Papers and Notes on Ostwald Color Theory, 1942-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Ray School of Photography Notes, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Northwestern University Evening School Notes, 1943-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 10-11)
  - American Red Cross Motor Corps of Chicago Notes, 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Chicago Institute of Design Notebooks, 1948-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 13-14)
  - Columbia University, Archival Resource Key (Box 27)
    - Academic Records and Papers, 1956-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Class Notes and Syllabi, 1956-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Class Notes, 1956-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 17-18)
  - "Unpublished Writings and Book Ideas" Notes, 1965-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - "Unpublished Writings and Book Ideas" Notes, 1972-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Small Notebook with Sketches, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - "Art Blooms on South Street" Drafts, 1986-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 3-4)
  - "Memories of Marion" Drafts, 1995-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 5)
    Handwritten and typescript drafts of article about Marion Morehouse.
  - "Working Philosophy - All Mediums", 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Essays and Notes, 1942-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Academic Papers and Notes, 1944-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Writings, 1996-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 9)
- Diaries, 1943-2001; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 2.1 Linear feet Boxes 28-30
  Thirty diaries by Maryette Charlton document travels and other aspects of her professional and personal life. Some contain drawings and others have information about her film projects. One diary contains drawings of Charlton by Alexander Calder. One additional diary was written by her mother Etna Barr Charlton. The addition to the Maryette Charlton papers arranged in series 16 contains a few journals.
  - Etna Barr Charlton Diary, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Maryette Charlton Diary, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Maryette Charlton Diary, 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Maryette Charlton Diary, 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Maryette Charlton Travel Diary, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Maryette Charlton Diary, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Maryette Charlton Mexico Trip Diary, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Maryette Charlton Colorado Trip Diary, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Maryette Charlton Diary, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Maryette Charlton Diary, 1952-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - Maryette Charlton Diary, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Maryette Charlton Diary, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Maryette Charlton Diary, 1953-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Maryette Charlton Diary, 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Maryette Charlton Diary, 1956-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 4)
    Includes Alexander Calder's drawings of Maryette Charlton, Delphine Seyrig, and Ellsworth Kelly.
  - Maryette Charlton Diary, 1956-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Maryette Charlton Diary, 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Maryette Charlton Diary, 1966-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Maryette Charlton Diary, 1968; 1973-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Maryette Charlton Diary, 1976-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Maryette Charlton Diary, 1978 August-1979 March; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 10)
    Includes entries on Richard Foreman film.
  - Maryette Charlton Diary, 1979 March-June; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Maryette Charlton Diary, 1979 June-October; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Maryette Charlton Diary, 1979 October-1980 September; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Maryette Charlton Diary, 1980 September-1982 September; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Maryette Charlton Diary, 1982-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Maryette Charlton "Trip to Cologne" Diary, 1986 August-September; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Maryette Charlton Diary, 1987-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Maryette Charlton Diary, 1990-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Maryette Charlton Diary, 1994-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 5)
- Teaching Files, 1946-1997; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 3.6 Linear feet Boxes 30-33, 80
  Teaching files document Maryette Charlton's career as an instructor at the Art Institute of Chicago and as the founder of and teacher at the art department at the American University of Beirut. Files include appointment calendars, schedules, notes, lectures, printed material, and photographs.
  5.1: Art Institute of Chicago, 1946-1976
  5.2: American University of Beirut, 1950-1997
  - Art Institute of Chicago, 1946-1976; 5.1; Archival Resource Key
    This subseries includes correspondence, appointment calendars, lecture notes and notebooks, administrative files, and various printed material related to Maryette Charlton's work as a lecturer and tour guide for exhibitions at the Art Institute of Chicago.
    The folders in this subseries are grouped together by document type, then arranged chronologically within each grouping.
    - Correspondence about Color Samples, 1947-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence about Speaking Engagements, 1950-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence and Notes from Helen Parker, circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Fullerton Sketch Class, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Artwork for School Programs and Events, 1950-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Appointment Calendars, 1948-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 11-13)
    - Notebooks, 1948-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 14-15)
    - Exhibition Catalogs and Tour Guide Lecture Notes, 1947-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 16-17)
    - Lecture Notes, 1948-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - Lecture Notes on Index Cards, 1946-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Lecture Announcements, 1950-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Conference and Convention Panels, 1949-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 31, Folder 3-4)
    - Employee List, 1949-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Weekly Bulletins, 1948-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 31, Folder 6-7)
    - News Releases, 1949-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Articles and News Clippings, 1948-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 31, Folder 9-10)
    - Printed Material, 1950-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Printed Material, 1950-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 32, Folder 1-2)
    - Holiday Magazine, 1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 32, Folder 3)
      Oversized material housed in Box 80.
    - Art Institute Director Daniel Catton Rich Obituary, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Oversized Holiday Magazine from Box 32, Folder 3, 1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 80)
  - American University of Beirut, 1950-1997; 5.2; Archival Resource Key
    This subseries consists of material related to Maryette Charlton's work as founder and professor of the American University of Beirut's Art Department. Files include appointment calendars, schedules, notes, lectures, exhibition and printed material, and photographs. There are additional photographs on Beirut in the photographic materials series.
    - Correspondence, Archival Resource Key (Box 32)
      - Buehr, George, 1955-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 32, Folder 5)
      - Chamoun, Zelpha, 1956-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 32, Folder 6)
      - Chamoun, Zelpha, circa 1955-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 32, Folder 7)
      - Hoff, Margo, 1950-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 32, Folder 8)
      - Hoff, Margo, 1987-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 32, Folder 9)
      - Miscellaneous, 1953-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Appointment Calendar, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Art Department, Archival Resource Key (Box 32)
      - Teaching Contracts, 1952-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 32, Folder 12)
      - Lecture Notes, 1952-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 32, Folder 13)
      - Seminar Notes and Class Attendance, 1952-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 32, Folder 14)
      - Course Catalogs, 1952-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 32, Folder 15-16)
      - Stationary, 1952-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - Hoff, Margo - Printed Material, circa 1953-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 32, Folder 18-19)
    - Hoff, Margo - Photographs, circa 1950-circa 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 32, Folder 20)
    - Young Artists of the Near East Exhibition Correspondence, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 32, Folder 21)
    - Young Artists of the Near East Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 32, Folder 22)
    - Young Artists of the Near East Exhibition Printed Material, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Writings and Photographs on University History, 1976-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Art Seminar Pamphlets, 1955-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - University Bulletins, 1971-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Articles about Jafet Library Exhibitions, 1956-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Clippings about Maryette Charlton and Art Department, 1952-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 6-7)
    - Clippings on "Middle East Information", 1951-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Alumni Magazines and Newsletters, 1951-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 9-10)
    - Al-Kulliyah Magazine, 1953-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 11-12)
    - The American University of Beirut, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Lebanon: The Artist's View, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - La Revue du Liban Magazine, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 15)
      Oversize material housed in Box 80.
    - Life Magazine Image Reprints, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - Printed Material, 1954-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 17-19)
    - Photographs of "Liaisons in Lebanon", circa 1952-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 20)
    - Photographs of Beirut Art Seminar Children's Classes, 1955-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 21)
    - Oversized La Revue du Liban Magazine from Box 33, Folder 15, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 80)
    - Oversized Life Magazine Image Reprints from Box 33, Folder 16, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 80)
- Professional and Project Files, 1923-1998; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 7.6 Linear feet Boxes 34-41, 81, OV 87
  Found here is documentation of Maryette Charlton's professional projects and work, memberships, commitees, grants, fellowships, conferences, and the film business in general. Many of the files document her founding of the University of Iowa Museum of Art, her work at the Chicago Public School Art Society, as a color analyst for the Container Corporation of America, and as executor of the the estate of artist Louise Medbery von Brockdorff. Files docuementing Charlton's major film projects are arranged in Series 7.
  6.1: University of Iowa Museum of Art, 1954-1998
  6.2: Other Professional and Project Files, 1923-1995
  - University of Iowa Museum of Art, 1954-1998; 6.1; Archival Resource Key
    Maryette Charlton founded the University of Iowa Museum of Art together with Leone and Owen Elliott. Arranged here is correspondence between Charlton and the Elliotts and material on the art collections they donated to the museum. Files include business correspondence with museum administrators, annual reports, printed material, and photographs. There are also 7 sound cassettes and 10 microcassettes, mostly of recordings of conversations between Maryette Charlton and Leone Elliott, who were close friends.
    - Correspondence, Archival Resource Key (Box 34)
      - General Correspondence, 1997-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 1)
      - Hobbs, Robert C., 1984-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 2)